http://www.experian.com/privacy/ccpa-privacy-policy.html

LAST UPDATED:  July 1, 2020
This section contains disclosures required by the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) and applies only to “personal information” that is subject to the CCPA.
Personal Information We Collect, Disclose for a Business Purpose, and Sell. We collect the categories of personal information about California consumers identified in the chart below. As further set forth in the chart below, in the past 12 months, we have disclosed and sold California consumers’ personal information to third parties for business or commercial purposes.
Categories of Personal Information
Collected in the last 12 months:
Categories of sources from which information has been collected:
Business or commercial purposes for collection, use, and sharing:
Disclosed for business purposes to the following categories of third parties:
May be sold to the following categories of third parties:
Personal and online identifiers (such as first and last name, email address, or unique online identifiers)
Yes
• Lifestyle & Interest Product Companies
• Other Product Companies Not Categorized
• Parenting Product Companies
• Public Records
• Publishing Product Companies
• Telecommunications Companies
• Other Authorized Data Compilers
• Online & Mobile Websites & Apps
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Categories of information described in Section 1798.80(e) of the California Civil Code (such as physical characteristics or description, insurance policy number, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information)
Yes
• Other Authorized Data Compilers
• Consumer Survey Companies
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Characteristics of protected classifications under California or federal law (such as race or gender)
Yes
• Parenting Product Companies
• Consumer Survey Companies
• Public Records
• Other Companies Not Categorized
• Other Authorized Data Compilers
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Commercial or transactions information (such as records of personal property or products or services purchased, obtained or considered)
Yes
• Apparel & Accessory Companies
• Gift Product Companies
• Health Product Companies
• Other Product Companies Not Categorized
• Parenting Product Companies
• Business to Business Companies
• Financial Services Companies
• Other Authorized Data Compilers
• Public Records
• Publishing Product Companies
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Internet or other electronic network activity information (such as browsing history, search history, interactions with a website, email, application, or advertisement)
Yes
• Apparel & Accessory Companies
• Automotive Companies
• Business to Business Companies
• Consumer Packaged Goods Companies
• Consumer Survey Companies
• Electronics Companies
• Financial Services Companies
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Biometric information (such as call recordings)
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
N/A
Geolocation information
Yes
• Online & Mobile Websites & Apps
• Telecommunications Companies
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Sensory information (such as audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information)
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
N/A
Professional or employment-related information
Yes
• Consumer Survey Companies
• Business to Business Companies
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Consumer Survey Companies
Commercial Purposes:
• Marketing
• Helping businesses find new customers
• Developing insights as to consumer interests and behaviors
• Keeping contact information up to date and relevant
• Enabling relevant and personalized marketing messages
• Location services
• Analytics
• Decisioning
• Fraud and identify theft prevention and protection
• Commercial credit reporting
• Research and development
• Debt recovery
Business Purposes:
• Auditing
• Internal research
• Quality control
• Improving our services
• Legal compliance
• Advertising and marketing products
• Communicate with consumers about our services
• To detect and protect against security incidents
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Inferences drawn from the above information about your predicted characteristics and preferences
No
N/A
N/A
N/A
• Automotive Companies
• Business Services/Agency
• Consumer Services Companies
• Educational Institutions & Companies
• Travel, Leisure & Entertainment Companies
Your Rights Regarding Personal Information. California residents have certain rights with respect to the personal information collected by businesses. If you are a California resident, you may exercise the following rights regarding your personal information, subject to certain exceptions and limitations:
The right to know the categories and specific pieces of personal information we collect, use, disclose, and sell about you, the categories of sources from which we collected your personal information, our purposes for collecting or selling your personal information, the categories of your personal information that we have either sold or disclosed for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties with which we have shared personal information;
- The right to request that we delete the personal information we have collected from you.
We use a two-step process for online requests to delete. You will be asked to clearly submit your request to delete and to separately confirm your choice.
The right to opt out of our sale(s) of your personal information. Please note that if you opt out of certain types of sales, we will be unable to provide you with the services that rely on such sales.
The right not to receive discriminatory treatment for the exercise of the privacy rights conferred by the CCPA.
To exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the following information and submit the required verifying information, as further described below:
Online at experian.com/ccpa
By phone at 1-833-210-4615
By mail at PO Box 703, Allen, TX 75013
Verification Process and Required Information. Note that we may need to request additional information from you to verify your identity or understand the scope of your request, although you will not be required to create an account with us to submit a request or have it fulfilled. In order to exercise your rights under the CCPA, we will require you to provide, at a minimum first name, last name, social security number, and address. For requests submitted by mail, you will need to send copies of two forms of identification that include your first name, last name and current address.
Authorized Agent. You may designate an authorized agent to make a CCPA request on your behalf by mailing two forms of identification showing your first name, last name and current address and a signed authorization allowing an agent to request information on your behalf.
Minors’ Right to Opt In. We do not sell the personal information of minors under 16 years of age.
Contact for More Information. For questions or concerns about Experian’s privacy policy or practices, please contact us by mail at:
Compliance Department Experian 475 Anton Blvd. Costa Mesa, CA 92626
Industries
Automotive
Banks
Credit Unions
Debt Collection
Energy/Utilities
Fintech
Health
Contact Us
©2020 Experian Information Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
Experian and the Experian trademarks used herein are trademarks or registered trademarks of Experian. Other product or company names mentioned herein are the property of their respective owners.
